（屏幕呼啸）
(screen whooshing)
（贴纸弹出）
(sticker popping)
（屏幕呼啸）
(screen whooshing)
- 加载自定义数据集。
- Loading a custom dataset.
尽管 Hugging Face Hub 主持
Although the Hugging Face Hub hosts
超过一千个公共数据集，
over a thousand public datasets,
你经常需要处理数据
you'll often need to work with data
存储在你的笔记本电脑或某些远程服务器上。
that is stored on your laptop or some remote server.
在本视频中，我们将探讨数据集库如何
In this video, we'll explore how the Datasets library
可用于加载不可用的数据集
can be used to load datasets that aren't available
在 Hugging Face Hub 上。
on the Hugging Face Hub.
正如你在此表中所见，Datasets 库
As you can see in this table, the Datasets library
提供了几个内置脚本
provides several in-built scripts
以多种格式加载数据集。
to load datasets in several formats.
要以其中一种格式加载数据集，
To load a dataset in one of these formats,
你只需要提供格式的名称
you just need to provide the name of the format
到 load_dataset 函数，
to the load_dataset function,
连同 data_files 参数
along with a data_files argument
指向一个或多个文件路径或 URL。
that points to one or more filepaths or URLs.
要查看实际效果，让我们从加载 CSV 文件开始。
To see this in action, let's start by loading a CSV file.
在这个例子中，我们首先下载一个数据集
In this example, we first download a dataset
关于来自 UCI 机器学习库的葡萄酒质量。
about wine quality from the UCI machine learning repository.
由于这是一个 CSV 文件，因此我们指定
Since this is a CSV file, we then specify
CSV 加载脚本。
the CSV loading script.
现在，这个脚本需要知道我们的数据在哪里，
Now, this script needs to know where our data is located,
所以我们提供文件名
so we provide the filename
作为 data_files 参数的一部分。
as part of the data_files argument.
并且加载脚本还允许你
And the loading script also allows you
传递几个关键字参数，
to pass several keyword arguments,
所以在这里我们也指定了
so here we've also specified
分隔符是分号。
that the separator is a semi-colon.
这样，我们就可以看到数据集
And with that, we can see the dataset
作为 DatasetDict 对象自动加载，
is loaded automatically as a DatasetDict object,
CSV 文件中的每一列都表示为一个特征。
with each column in the CSV file represented as a feature.
如果你的数据集位于 GitHub 等远程服务器上
If your dataset is located on some remote server like GitHub
或其他一些存储库，
or some other repository,
这个过程实际上非常相似。
the process is actually very similar.
唯一的区别是现在 data_files 参数
The only difference is that now the data_files argument
指向 URL 而不是本地文件路径。
points to a URL instead of a local filepath.
现在让我们看一下加载原始文本文件。
Let's now take a look at loading raw text files.
这种格式在 NLP 中很常见，
This format is quite common in NLP,
你通常会找到书籍和戏剧
and you'll typically find books and plays
只是一个包含原始文本的文件。
are just a single file with raw text inside.
在这个例子中，我们有一个莎士比亚戏剧的文本文件
In this example, we have a text file of Shakespeare plays
存储在 GitHub 存储库中。
that's stored on a GitHub repository.
正如我们对 CSV 文件所做的那样，
And as we did for CSV files,
我们只需选择文本加载脚本
we simply choose the text loading script
并将 data_files 参数指向 URL。
and point the data_files argument to the URL.
如你所见，这些文件是逐行处理的，
As you can see, these files are processed line-by-line,
所以原始文本中的空行也被表示
so empty lines in the raw text are also represented
作为数据集中的一行。
as a row in the dataset.
对于 JSON 文件，有两种主要格式需要了解。
For JSON files, there are two main formats to know about.
第一个叫做 JSON 行，
The first one is called JSON Lines,
文件中的每一行都是一个单独的 JSON 对象。
where every row in the file is a separate JSON object.
对于这些文件，你可以加载数据集
For these files, you can load the dataset
通过选择 JSON 加载脚本
by selecting the JSON loading script
并将 data_files 参数指向文件或 URL。
and pointing the data_files argument to the file or URL.
在这个例子中，我们加载了一个 JSON 行文件
In this example, we've loaded a JSON lines files
基于 Stack Exchange 问题和答案。
based on Stack Exchange questions and answers.
另一种格式是嵌套的 JSON 文件。
The other format is nested JSON files.
这些文件基本上看起来像一本巨大的字典，
These files basically look like one huge dictionary,
所以 load_dataset 函数允许你指定
so the load_dataset function allow you to specify
要加载哪个特定密钥。
which specific key to load.
例如，用于问答的 SQuAD 数据集
For example, the SQuAD dataset for question and answering
有它的格式，我们可以通过指定来加载它
has its format, and we can load it by specifying
我们对数据字段感兴趣。
that we're interested in the data field.
最后一件事要提
There is just one last thing to mention
关于所有这些加载脚本。
about all of these loading scripts.
你可以有不止一次分裂，
You can have more than one split,
你可以通过将数据文件视为字典来加载它们，
you can load them by treating data files as a dictionary,
并将每个拆分名称映射到其对应的文件。
and map each split name to its corresponding file.
其他一切都保持完全不变
Everything else stays completely unchanged
你可以看到一个加载的例子
and you can see an example of loading
此 SQuAD 的训练和验证拆分均在此处。
both the training and validation splits for this SQuAD here.
这样，你现在可以从笔记本电脑加载数据集，
And with that, you can now load datasets from your laptop,
Hugging Face Hub，或任何其他地方。
the Hugging Face Hub, or anywhere else want.
（屏幕呼啸）
(screen whooshing)